Hi guys will welcome back.
So what next.
Now we have the project management plan and with project management plan we have a lot of other information.
And if you're wondering I haven't talked about Bluebeard's and all those kind of creations then don't
really I will address all of that.
I'm moving in the way it's mentioned in the pinball guide so that it's easier not only to understand
the process of project management but also is helpful for those who are preparing for the exams.
So OK so what is direct and manage project work in simple language.
Your daily project management Verd is direct and manage the project for it's nothing else.
So what a project management does.
After creating a project man which is the implementation part is being done here.
And as I mentioned about they know teachers in certain activities are performed to project charter and
project management plan creation happens at the predefined stage is irrelevant.
In the case of an entire project where does this activity direct and manage project work.
As you can expect happens throughout the project because Project Managers need to do the project management
throughout the project delivery delay closing the project so it's very important to stay vigilant.
And these are the important tools and techniques and the outputs.
So project management plan any component so any component simply means that it could be let's say there
is only scope management plan or only WPA.
So only cost.
So whatever document is created as part of project management plan creation activity is going to work
as the input here.
Then of course we have all the project documents like change.
Lessons learned registered lessons learn register could come from the previous projects.
So if at the end of the projects you have to perform this activity where you review the project how
it went.
What worked and what went bad.
And the root causes to all of that will be in part here as lessons learned.
Then we have milestone lists project communications schedule requirement disability metrics are just
coming from the business analysis or whoever is working on the requirements could just report on all
that data.
And of course mental factors and the organizational process sex all of that is part of your input here.
Because think of any project lets say we are moving our application to our software which our company
used to cloud not in this case.
We will have a business case.
This business case will be something like the cloud is more secure cloud is faster its sheeple from
convinced hosting.
So that will become your business case then that business case will be used to build a project charter
that project charter will become your document well and which will justify not only the existence of
a project management plan but also will justify will also include details like you know constraints
assumptions high level requirement cost and schedule things like that.
And then that will work as the input for project management plan creation.
Once you have the project management plan you need to work on the actual project management.
And for anything and everything which was done as part of the recommendation research for this movement
to the cloud.
We work as input and as its referred to a general management practices the tools and techniques our
expert judgment Project Management Information Systems meetings and the output of this activity would
be deliverable.
So in this case the movement of the cloud the movement of the application to the cloud the final deployment
of the production would be your deliverables and of course all of their documents so at the end of this
project you're going to create a lessons learned register and you will have a project management plan
project charter document business analysis documents testing results.
All of that will be deliverable performance did issued law change first and all of that and you can
see that anything and everything that was done and completed as part of this project and becomes our
output of this and therefore the organizational process of such subjects So basically let's say there
was a template change done as part of this project and you did the central repository of the organization
which will be done as part of our organization process or sets of dates and these are some of the major
activities which are performed as part of project management activities so you have to validate that
scope you have to control this group control the schedule cost quality resources.
Then you have to monitor the communication risk.
You have to also work on the procurement.
If it is needed then you have Mannas the knowledge management side of a project an integrated change
control document updates a stakeholder engagement.
These are some of the most common activities which are needed to be done in a project in the next we
do.
We will talk about managing project knowledge.
So that's it for now.
Thank you.